Hello English learners,
welcome back to English
Pod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we're
going to be taking
you to the airport.
That's right, we're going to
listen as a man checks in at
the airport and deals
with his luggage.
That's right, so we're going
to be looking at a lot of
great stuff that can
help you the next time
you are at the airport
at the check-in counter.
So why don't we take a
look at one word that we're
going to preview today
in vocabulary preview.
We're going to hear this guy
say I'd like to check three pieces.
He's going to check
three pieces of what?
Pieces of luggage.
So when we talk about
luggage, we can say
pieces of luggage. That's
right, luggage is a non-count noun. So you
can't say one luggage, two luggage is three
luggage. That's wrong. Right,
so we use pieces of luggage.
Okay, so three pieces
of luggage. Very good.
Let's listen to our
dialogue for the first time.
We're going to see what
happens with this guy
at the airport and with
his pieces of luggage.
Next, please. Hello, sir. May
I see your passport, please?
Yes. Here you go. Will you
be checking any bags today?
Yes, I'd like to
check three pieces.
I'm sorry, sir. Airline
policy only allows
two pieces of check luggage at 20 kilograms
each plus one piece of carry-on luggage.
I will have to charge you
extra for the additional suitcase.
What? Why? I'm taking
an intercontinental flight.
I'm flying 16,000 kilometers.
How am I supposed to take only
two 20 kilo bags that's absurd?
I'm sorry, sir. There's
nothing I can do.
You cannot board the flight
with that large bag either.
Carry-on bags must fit in
the overhead compartment
or under your seat. That
bag is clearly too big.
Now I see. You charge
next to nothing for an
international ticket. When
it comes to charging for
any other small thing, you
charge an arm and a leg.
So tell me, miss, how
much will I have to pay
for all of this? Let's see. 625 US dollar.
That's more than my round trip ticket.
All right. Well, that's a
whole lot of money, isn't
it? Well, I think it's a
very common situation.
I'm sure many of our listeners
can relate to this situation.
Overweight charges are
pretty expensive very high.
I know from personal experience, but
that's not what we want to talk about.
Now we want to talk about
some really useful vocabulary
in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
All right. On language takeaway
today, we have five words.
So why don't we
start with the first one?
So the woman asked, will you
be checking any bags today?
Will you be checking
any bags today?
To check bags. Right.
So the verb to check,
it means to to give
your bags to the airline
to register them. Okay.
So that's what happens
with your luggage. You
check them. So basically,
they become responsible
for your bags. Right.
It reminds me of
checking into a hotel.
Right. Very similar.
When you go to a hotel,
you register at the
hotel. You check in.
In this case, you just check your luggage.
You don't check in your luggage.
Right. Okay. So check
luggage. So you wanted to
check three pieces of
luggage and he also had
carry on luggage. Carry
on luggage. Carry on.
So carry on luggage,
it's pretty simple.
That's right. You carry
it on yourself. Exactly.
You carry it on to the plane.
Now we can we can talk
about carry on luggage.
Right. Or carry on bag.
Right. Or carry on suitcase.
A very small suitcase
that can fit under your
seat. Exactly. All right.
So carry on luggage.
Now he was traveling on an
intercontinental flight. Intercontinental.
Intercontinental. We have two words there.
Inter between between,
right? And continental.
So this sounds like continent.
Okay. So he's traveling
maybe from Asia to North America. Okay.
Intercontinental. He's trying to board this
intercontinental flight.
So to board a flight.
Board a plane. Board a
train. All right. So basically,
it means to to get on to get on to get on a
vehicle. Okay. So I can say board the ship.
Board the car. No. No.
But board the board the
train board the train
board the bus. All aboard.
That's right. That's why in movies you
see that somebody will yell all aboard.
Yeah. And the train
station, right? Exactly.
All aboard. Okay. So
board a vehicle and our last
phrase for today.
Overhead compartment.
Overhead compartment. All right.
Let's break this phrase
down. Overhead.
So that's on top of your
head, right? Exactly. Yeah.
Above you. Yeah. And
the compartment is a
place where you can put
something and store it.
Mm-hmm. Kind of
like a box. Right. Yeah.
So you have an overhead
compartment that big box where
you put your bags and your
purse or whatever on an airplane.
Mm-hmm. Very similar
to, for example, an
overhead projector.
Right. So that's the machine
that puts an image
or a picture on a wall.
Like sometimes you see
them in meetings. Right.
So because the image is
over your head and it's big,
it's called an overhead
projector. Okay.
So some great language.
Why don't we hear it again in
context by listening to the
dialogue for the second time?
Next, please.
Hello, sir. May I see
your passport, please?
Yes. Here you go.
Will you be checking any
bags today? Yes. I'd like to check
if three pieces. I'm
sorry, sir. Airline policy
allows only two pieces
of checked luggage at 20
kilograms each plus one
piece of carry-on luggage.
I will have to charge you
extra for the additional
suitcase. What? Why? I'm
taking an intercontinental flight.
I'm flying 16,000 kilometers.
How am I supposed to
take only two 20 kilo bags?
That's absurd. I'm sorry,
sir. There's nothing I can do.
You cannot board
the flight with that
large bag either. Carry-on
bags must fit in the
overhead compartment
or under your seat.
That bag is clearly too big.
Now I see. You charge next to
nothing for an
international ticket.
But when it comes to charging
for any other small thing,
you charge an arm and
a leg. So tell me, miss,
how much will I have
to pay for all this?
Let's see. $625. You have dollars.
That's more than my round trip ticket.
All right. So I think it's a
little bit more clear now.
And with this,
it's time for us to
take a look at some great phrases in
putting it together. Putting it together.
So this guy was pretty
angry about this airline policy.
And he said, how
am I supposed to?
How am I supposed to?
Okay. So before we
get into explaining this,
why don't we listen to a couple of examples
so we can try and understand what it means?
Example one. How am I
supposed to fit the dog in the car?
There are 10 people
in there already.
Example two. How is she supposed
to get to work if her car's in the shop?
Example three. How are we supposed to
know the answer to that? It's impossible.
Okay. So I can understand
that it means how can I do this?
Right. How do you expect me to do this?
How is it possible for me to do this?
Very good. It's a phrase you
use when you're frustrated, right?
Yeah, exactly. You're
maybe a little bit frustrated
or you're maybe nervous
of something that you
can't do or don't know
how. Yeah, this phrase, it's
not impolite, but it sort
of gives the idea that you're
challenging the other
person a little bit.
Maybe, yeah. Okay. So a
good phrase that you can use on
different situations and
you can try and mix it
up with different verbs,
right? Right. All right.
Now let's take a look
at our next phrase.
I'm sorry, sir. There's nothing I
can do. There's nothing I can do.
There's nothing I can do.
So basically, the woman
can't help the man, even
though he's insisting and he's pushing that
he wants another solution. Yeah. Right.
So finally, she says, I'm
sorry, there's nothing I can do.
So we use this phrase
when someone's pushing you
too much, right? Right.
And you would use it only in
that situation towards
the end because it is a little
bit, it's it's strong.
It's not implied, but it's
just you're saying, you
know what, I'm sorry, there's
I can't do anything about
it. Now let's move on
to our third phrase. You
charge next to nothing.
Next to nothing. Next to
nothing. Next to nothing.
All right. So we're
talking about charging,
we're talking about
money. Why don't we listen
to some examples of
what this next to nothing
phrase means? Example one. Do you like my
new house? It was so cheap that it almost
costs next to
nothing. Example two.
Let's go to Thailand. Take its
cost next to nothing right now.
Example three. The real estate agent charged
me next to nothing for his commission.
So it got a really good deal.
So when something costs next to
nothing, it's really cheap,
right? It's really cheap,
or you consider it to be
cheap. And now for our
last phrase, it's the
complete opposite of next to
nothing. Right. Charge
an arm and a leg.
An arm and a leg. All right. So
this means it's really expensive.
It's so expensive.
It's like giving
your arm and your leg.
Right. To pay for it. Yeah.
Very good. So next to nothing. Really
cheap. An arm and a leg. Really expensive.
Can we look at the
use here? All right.
So when the dialogue we heard,
you charge an arm and a leg.
But we can also say it
costs an arm and a leg.
Right. Because we are
referring to money, right?
All right. So some
great phrases here.
Now I think it's time we listen
to our dialogue one more time.
Next, please. Hello, sir. May
I see your passport, please?
Yes. Here you go. Will you
be checking any bags today?
Yes. I'd like to
check three pieces.
I'm sorry, sir. Airline
policy only allows
two pieces of check luggage at 20 kilograms
each plus one piece of carry-on luggage.
I will have to charge you
extra for the additional suitcase.
What? Why? I'm taking
an intercontinental flight.
I'm flying 16,000 kilometers.
How am I supposed
to take only two 20
kilo bags? That's absurd.
I'm sorry, sir. There's
nothing I can do.
You cannot board the flight
with that large bag either.
Carry-on bags must fit in
the overhead compartment
or under your seat. That
bag is clearly too big.
Now I see. You charge
the next to nothing for an
international ticket.
When it comes to charging
for any other small thing,
you charge an arm and a leg.
So tell me, miss. How
much will I have to pay
for all of this? Let's
see. 625 US dollar.
That's more than my
round-trip ticket. Okay, so airline
policies, luggage, it's
always a problem, right?
Most of the time you always
end up paying overweight
when you travel. Yeah, I
know that this happened
to me once and it
was really expensive.
Really, what happened? I was
flying on an intercontinental
flight from India back
to Europe and I had
too many extra bags, but I
really needed to bring them.
And so it cost
me $6,000. $6,000.
Yeah. Wow. So my credit card was pretty
maxed out after that. That's incredible.
Yeah. Well, I'm sure
many of our users probably
suffered similar
experiences like this.
So please come to our website and
share it with us at EnglishPod.com.
That's right. Marco and
I are always around to
answer your questions.
So please check us out
and thanks for downloading you guys.
Until next time, bye.